Orochimaru's Return
This is Kabuto?
（水月）これが　カブト？
なんか　キモイね。
He's kind of gross, huh?
この腹から出てるのなんて
まるで　でっかい…。
This one coming out of
his gut looks like a huge—
Just leave him be.
（サスケ）そいつは　もう放っておけ。
（重吾）生きているな。
She's alive.
What do you want with me
at this point?
今さら　お前らが
俺に何の用だ？
わざわざ　俺を捜してまで。
Why'd you go out of your way
to look for me?
Oh yeah! That's right. See…
うん　そうそう！
それが　その…。
すごいのアジトで
見つけちゃってさ。
We found something incredible
in one of the hideouts.
えっと。
Now let's see…
（重吾）さっき　イタチとお前が→
Earlier, you said that you and Itachi
stopped the Reanimation, right?
カブトの穢土転生を
止めたと言ったな。
だが　マダラとかいう穢土転生は
止まっていないようだぞ。
But I don't think it worked
on the reanimated Madara.
((イタチ：里が　どんなに
闇や矛盾を抱えていようと→
No matter what darkness or
contradictions lie within the village,
俺は　木ノ葉のうちはイタチだ。
I am still Itachi Uchiha of the Leaf!
（シスイ）
頼めるのは　親友のお前だけだ。
You're the only person
I can count on, my best friend.
この里を
うちはの名を守ってくれ。
Please protect this village…
and the honor of the Uchiha name.
I told you,
there's something I must do.
(言ったはずだ。　やらなければ
ならないことがあると))
そうか　止まっていないのか。
I see.
So it hasn't been stopped.
I'm talking to Sasuke!
Don't interrupt me.
僕が　サスケと話してんの！
水をささないでくれる！
Anyway, never mind that.
…と　そんなことより　これ。
Look!
Look, look!
見てみてみ！
な？　すごいでしょ。
See! Amazing, right?!
これがあれば　僕たち鷹が
この忍の世界を…。
With this, we Taka can rule
the shinobi world!
This is it…
これだ…。
ん？
すべてを知る人間…。
The human who's all-knowing…
I have to meet up with someone.
とりあえず　会わなければならない
やつができた。
俺は行く。
えっ　誰？
I'm leaving.
Huh? Who?
大蛇丸だ。
Orochimaru.
Huh?!
はあ？　なに言ってんの。
What are you talking about?
大蛇丸は
キミが　ぶっ殺したはずじゃ…。
You killed Orochimaru!
僕は　キミがこれを…。
I thought you would use this to…
Are you really surprised someone as
tenacious as Orochimaru
あのしぶとい男のことだ。
あれくらいで消え去るものか。
might not be killed so easily?
あの胸クソ悪い
大蛇丸に会ってでも→
And even if I do find him vile…
やってもらわなければ
ならないことがある。
I need him to do something for me.
一族　里。
The clan…
The village…
すべてを知る人間に会いに行く。
It's time to see the all-knowing.
大蛇丸に会うって
どういうこと？
What do you mean,
“see” Orochimaru?
Who is this all-knowing person?
すべてを知る人間って何なの？
お前らには　関係のないことだ。
You don't need to know.
What? I don't get it.
何だよ　わけわかんないね。
んなことより　大蛇丸を
復活させるなんてダメだ。
In any case,
Orochimaru must never be resurrected!
その巻物の力を使うのに→
You probably want to ask
Orochimaru for help
in using the power of the scroll, right?
大蛇丸にお願いする
つもりなんだろうけど→
時間をかければ　キミにだって
できるようになるって。
Just give it time and
you'll figure it out.
そう思ったからこそ
キミを捜して　わざわざこうして。
That's why we looked for you and…
大蛇丸でなければ
できないこともある。
There are still things only
Orochimaru can do.
サスケ　キミはさ→
Sasuke, tell me…
言ってみれば　大蛇丸の→
You were Orochimaru's
favorite pupil, right?
いちばんお気に入りの
弟子だったわけだろ。
なら　キミにだって。
水月　お前…。
So why can't you…?
Suigetsu!
Listen.
な　何？
大蛇丸をなめすぎだ。
Huh? What?
Don't underestimate Orochimaru.
Idiot!
バ　バカ！　全然なめてなんかないよ！
I don't underestimate him!
むしろ　その逆だって！
It's the exact opposite!
キミが　大蛇丸を倒せたのは
たまたま　やつの両腕が→
You were able to bring
down Orochimaru
only because both his arms
屍鬼封尽で使い物に
ならなくなってただけさ！
were useless from
the Reaper Death Seal, that's all.
キミのほうこそ
やつをなめてる。
You're the one
who's underestimating him!
仮に　やつが復活したとしても
おそらく　両腕は使えないだろう。
Even if he is revived,
his arms will probably still be useless.
でも　だからって　やばい。
また　キミの体は狙われるよ！
But he'll still be dangerous.
He's going to come after
your body again!
やつが　この戦争を知ったら
乗っからないわけがない。
If he finds out about this war,
he's going to want to be a part of it.
やつも　木ノ葉を潰したいんだし。
He wants to destroy the Leaf too!
そしたら　僕ら鷹も→
And that means that Team Taka
will get mixed up in this war!
一戦　交えなきゃ
ならないじゃないかよ！
いいの？
Are you okay with that?
下克上は成功したんだし→
We succeeded in beating
our superiors.
もう僕らの時代なんだって。
It's our time now!
今さら　大蛇丸なんて→
Who'd want to see Orochimaru now?
誰も見たくないし
ひっかきまわされたくもないしさ。
Hasn't he caused us
enough trouble?
少し黙ってろ　水月。
Shut up, Suigetsu.
それより　そこのカブトの体の一部を
えぐって持ってきてくれ。
Cut out and bring me
a piece of Kabuto's flesh.
え…。
Huh?
人の言うこと聞かないのに
人が言うことを聞くと思う？
You don't listen to me,
but you expect me to listen to you?
なら　俺がやる。
I'll do it.
はぁ…　やっぱ　こんな感じか。
It's always like this…
重吾は　ほんと　それでいいの？
Jugo, are you okay with this?
大蛇丸が復活しちゃうんだぜ。
Orochimaru's going to
be resurrected, you know…
かまわん。
サスケの意志は　君麻呂の意志だ。
I don't care.
Sasuke's will is Kimimaro's will.
俺は　それに従う。
I will abide by it.
グエ～。　キミもだけど
だいたい　何なの？　これ。
You're just the same.
What is going on with all of this?
俺の里では
これを仙人化という。
In my village,
we call it Sage Transformation.
もともと　俺の変化もそれだ。
My transformation originally
was the same thing.
ただし　俺のコピーは
呪印化と言ってたがな。
But in all of my clones, it's called
the Curse Mark Transformation.
((カカシ：お前の呪印を封印する。
I'm going to seal your Curse Mark.
(封邪法印！))
Curse Sealing!
《あれの逆…》
So the reverse of it is:
Curse Unsealing!
解邪法印！
うわっ！
（大蛇丸）
まさか　キミたちのほうから→
Who could have imagined…
that it would be you who
would facilitate my return!
私を復活させてくれるとはね。
ど…　どうも　お久しぶりっす。
H-Hello there! Long time no see.
大蛇丸　あんたに
やってもらいたいことがある。
Orochimaru, there's something
I want you to do for me.
（大蛇丸）そんなこと
いちいち説明しなくてもいいわ。
Don't bother explaining.
アンコの中で　ずっと見てたから。
I've been watching from
inside Anko this whole time.
呪印は　私の仙術チャクラを
流し込んだもの。
I secured My Sage Jutsu Chakra
into those Curse Marks.
それは
分離した私の意識でもある。
They are like pieces of
my consciousness.
なら　戦争のことも知ってるのか？
もちろん。
Then you know about the war too?
Of course.
ただ　それについて
一つだけ言っておくわ　水月。
I just have one thing to say
about that, Suigetsu.
Huh?
私　この戦争には興味ないから。
えっ！？
I have absolutely no interest
in this war.
Huh?!
もう他人が始めてしまった
戦争だしね。
It's someone else's war.
いまだに興味があるとすれば→
The only thing I'm interested
in right now…
サスケ君　あなたの
その若い体くらいよ。
Sasuke…
is your young body!
《それ　みたことか》
I told you!
と言っても
今の私には　それを→
Having said that, I don't currently
have the power to steal it.
奪えるほどの力はないしね。
《どうだかね》
I wouldn't be so sure…
やつに会って　どうするつもり？
What is your intent
in meeting with them?
俺は…　あまりに何も知らない。
There's too much that I don't know.
やつらに　すべてを聞く。
So I plan to ask them everything.
すべて？
Everything?
そんなこと
知らなくてもいいじゃない。
There's no need to know it all.
キミはまだ　子供なんだから。
You're still a child.
そうじゃない。
You're wrong.
((誰よりも　お前を子供扱いし→
I treated you like a child…
守るべき対象としてしか見ず→
I only tried to protect you.
I didn't trust your strength.
お前の力を信用していなかった。
だが　今はこう思う…。
But now, I believe…
お前が　父を母を→
that perhaps you could have
changed Father, Mother,
うちはを変えることが
できたかもしれないと…。
and the rest of the Uchiha.
俺が　はじめから
お前と　ちゃんと向き合い→
If I had been open
with you from the start…
(同じ目線に立って
真実を語り合っていれば…))
and looked you straight in the eyes
and told you the truth.
今は　もう子供じゃない…。
I'm not a child anymore.
子供ではいられない。
I can't stay a child.
((お前が
これから　どうなろうと…))
And no matter what you do
from here on out…
そもそもの始まりは
なんだったのか…。
I want to know what started it all.
俺は　どうあるべきであり
どう行動すべきなのか…。
What I'm supposed to be,
what I'm supposed to do.
復讐を迷っているの？
Are you questioning
your vengeance?
違う。
No…
復讐自体を
迷っているわけではない。
Not my quest for
vengeance itself.
イタチと再会し→
Reuniting with Itachi
made my hatred
前にも増して
木ノ葉への憎しみは強くなった。
towards the Hidden Leaf
grow even stronger.
ただ…　汚名を着せられ→
It's just…
I want to understand
how even in death,
死して　なお
木ノ葉の忍として里を思い→
Itachi could still consider
himself a Leaf Shinobi,
里を守ろうとした
イタチの　その気持とは…。
and care about and
try to protect the village
that dishonored his name.
イタチとは？　一族とは？
Who was Itachi? What is a clan?
What is a village?
里とは？　そして…。
And so…
すべてを知り
自分で考え　答えを出し→
I want to know everything,
so I can finally have the answer.
己の意志と眼で
成すべきことを見据えたい。
I need to see with my own eyes and
decide with my own mind
what I must do.
《イタチに操られ…。
He's no longer the Sasuke
who was manipulated by Itachi…
私や　トビに利用されていたときとは
もう違うようね…》
or me…or Tobi.
《なぜか　不思議な感覚…》
What a strange sensation.
カブトの力を　すべて吸い取って
殺すつもりだよ！
He's going to absorb all of
Kabuto's power, and then kill him!
用心したほうがいいって！
寝首をかかれるかもよ。
You better stay alert.
He might try and catch you
off guard too!
今のあなた…　悪くないわね。
The current you…isn't half bad.
ほら。
やっぱり　力を吸い取った！
Didn't I tell you?
He did absorb his power!
いや…　そうじゃない。
No, you're wrong.
仙人化を解き→
He undid the Sage Transformation.
カブトの中の
自分のチャクラを取っただけだ。
He's taken back his own chakra
that was inside Kabuto.
カブトのチャクラには
手をつけていないようだ。
He didn't touch Kabuto's chakra.
いいわ　協力してあげる。
Fine, I'll help you.
ついてきなさい。
場所は　どこだ？
Come along.
Where are we going?
フフフ…
あなたも　よく知ってる場所よ。
Someplace you're very familiar with.
えっ…。
さあ　行きましょう。
Let's be on our way.
（ガイ）さっき　魔像が→
The statue's been acting weird
since it swallowed something earlier.
何かを口に入れてから
様子が　おかしいぞ！
（ナルト）今の…。
That was…
まさか…。
Don't tell me…
（マダラ）本当なら　完全な状態で
復活させたかったのだがな。
I would have preferred
resurrecting it
in a completed state but…
Watch closely and feel it
through your skin…
よく見ておけ。
そして肌で感じろ。
The return of Ten Tails!
十尾復活を！
And the beginning of the end!
そして　世界の終わりの始まりを！
くっ。
So that's it!
そうか。　なら　その魔像が
十尾の素体だったってことか。
That statue was
the Ten Tails' actual body!
Huh?! What's Ten Tails?!
は？　なんだ　十尾ってば！
しかし　どういうことだ？
But what's going on?
When he declared war at
the Five Kage Summit…
五影会議で宣戦したときに
言い放ったとおりなら→
十尾復活のときに使う→
The purpose of this war
was to collect
九尾の尾獣チャクラを
回収するための戦争でしょ。
all nine Tailed Beasts' chakra
in order to revive Ten Tails.
八尾と九尾の回収は
まだ終わっていない。
He doesn't possess Eight Tails
or Nine Tails yet…
ハッタリか？
Is he bluffing?
《うかつに近づくのは
危険すぎる》
It's too risky to get up close.
（八尾）あ。
Oh…
((しかし　かけらでも
その力に変わりはない。
Only a fragment,
but it is not lacking in power.
俺のたこ足　１本分のチャクラ
やっちゃってる？
Have we given him one tentacle
arm's worth of chakra?
We're always dropping rhymes
(（ビー）俺たちいつも
韻を踏みつつ　ドジを踏む。　イエー))
But maybe we messed up big time…
Yay!
（ビー）前に　たこ足分身のチャクラを
少々　回収されてる。
The chakra from a tentacle
was taken, just a little
I may not look it
I admit I'm flustered a bit
こう見えても　少し慌ててる。
He took the chakra from one
of Eight Tails' tentacle arms…
八尾のたこ足のチャクラを。
なら　尾獣の一部でもいい
ということか。
Does that mean only a portion
of a Tailed Beast is sufficient?
（九尾）ナルト。
お前も感じたようだな。
Naruto…
You felt it too, didn't you?
あの壺と　ひょうたんの中に
わしのチャクラがあったことを。
That was my chakra in
that bottle and gourd.
うん。
Yup…
Let me take over, Naruto.
（九尾）代われ　ナルト。
わしが説明してやる。
I'll explain.
十尾についてもな。
About Ten Tails too.
You listen from in here.
お前も　ここで聞いてろ。
九喇嘛は
十尾のことを知ってんのか？
You know about Ten Tails, Kurama?
Yeah, of course.
ああ　もちろんだ。
Listen up, everyone!
（九尾）みんな聞け！
Hmm?
んっ？
その声！
That voice!
ナルトと九尾が入れ替わった。
Naruto switched places
with Nine Tails, pow!
いろいろと説明してくれる。
He'll explain everything to us…
九尾とナルトは　もう腹割った。
Nine Tails and Naruto
are tight now!
（九尾）尾獣の一部でもいい
ってんなら→
If even just a portion of
the Tailed Beast is sufficient…
すでに魔像には八尾とわしの
チャクラの一部が入ってる。
Then that statue already has a piece
of Eight Tails' and
my chakra inside it.
んっ　九尾も！？
The Nine Tails too?!
（九尾）さっきやつが口寄せし
魔像に食わせた→
The bottle and gourd that guy
summoned and fed
壺とひょうたんは
六道のジジイが持ってた宝具だ。
to the statue just now
were two of Old Man
Six Paths' treasured tools.
何でも封印しちまう
強力な封印術を持ち→
They both possess powerful
Sealing Jutsu
that can seal away anything
and everything.
入れられちまえば
何をしても出られねえ。
Once you get put inside either
one of them,
you can't get out,
no matter what.
So…
で　だ…
その壺のほうには金角。
Sealed inside the bottle
was a guy named Kinkaku.
And Ginkaku was sealed
inside the gourd.
ひょうたんには銀角ってのが
封印されて入ってた。
おそらく　穢土転生され
この戦争に利用されたあげく→
I suspect they were reanimated
using the Reanimation Jutsu,
used in the war and
then sealed away.
それらに封印されたんだろう。
六道仙人に金角　銀角。
Kinkaku and Ginkaku,
and the Sage of the Six Paths…
They're all legendary names…
伝説に聞く名前ばかりだぞ。
しかし　なぜ　それが
九尾チャクラと関係がある？
But what's the connection
with Nine Tails' chakra?
（九尾）かつて　やつら兄弟が→
There was a time when
the brothers challenged me to a battle.
わしに戦いを
挑んできたことがあった。
食ってやったがな。
Naturally, I devoured them.
However…
だが　その後→
They survived and fed on me
from the inside
やつらは　わしの腹の中で
わしの肉をむさぼり食い→
and absorbed my chakra.
わしのチャクラを吸収しおった。
つまり　金角　銀角は→
So Kinkaku and Ginkaku
had some of your chakra.
九尾のチャクラの一部を
持ってたってことだね。
そして　面の男は→
And the masked guy took them
as insurance,
それを十尾復活の
保険材料として奪っておいた。
for the revival of the Ten Tails…
ダルイ第１部隊から。
from Darui's First Company.
そこは本部からの情報と一致する。
That's consistent with
the report we got from HQ.
（九尾）だが　八尾とわしの
チャクラのかけらだけに→
But given that they're just fragments
of Eight Tails' and my chakra,
十尾が　どんな形で復活するかは
わからん。
who knows what form or shape
the revived Ten Tails will take.
なるべく復活する前に
なんとかしたいものだな。
We must act before Ten Tails
fully comes back to life.
カカシ。
Kakashi…
お前は　そうやって簡単に
口を開く。
You speak your mind
way too easily.
後悔ばかりの生涯を
送るにふさわしい男だ。
You're a man for whom
a life full of regrets is fitting!
お前　いったい　本当に何者だ？
Just…who the hell are you anyway?
顔を覚えないお前に
それを教える意味があるのか？
What's the point in telling someone
who can't remember faces?
（九尾）カカシ…
お前の言うように→
Kakashi, like you said,
if we're going to make a move,
やるなら　十尾が復活する前の
今しかない。
now's the chance, before
the Ten Tails is revived fully.
十尾が完全復活するときは
この世の終わりを意味すると→
Old Man Six Paths used to say
that Ten Tails' full revival
would signify the end of the world.
六道のジジイは　言っていた。
そんなに　十尾ってすげえのか？
Is the Ten Tails really that terrible?
尾が１０本あるのは
想像できっけど→
I get that he's got Ten Tails,
but just how powerful is he?
いったい　どんなのだ？
一尾から九尾である　わしまでの
チャクラの集合体であり→
He's the aggregate of the chakra
of all the Tailed Beasts,
One Tail through me.
チャクラの始まりであり
国づくりの神だ。
He was the beginning of chakra
and a creator-god of many nations.
天目一箇神　ダタラ　デイダラボッチ
いろいろと名がある。
Amenohitotsunokami…
Datara… Deidarabotchi…
He has many names.
海を飲み地を裂き　山を運んで→
He drank oceans,
split open the earth,
and hoisted up mountains…
この世を作ったとされる祖
そのもの。
He is the progenitor who is said
to have created this very land.
単純に考えても
尾獣九体を足した強さだ。
Simply put, he has the total power
of all nine Tailed Beasts.
わし一体じゃ　およびもつかん。
Honestly, I couldn't take him on
by myself and hope to win.
正直な。
（九尾）だが　もっとも
チャクラの強いわしや→
But if he only has a piece
of Eight Tails and me,
八尾の一部しか
入ってないとなると→
who has the most chakra
out of the nine…
やってみるまでは　わからねえ。
it might be worth a try.
お前らは　勘違いをしている。
You're all mistaken.
俺にとって十尾復活は
完全である必要はない。
For me, the revival of Ten Tails
doesn't need to be complete.
俺の目的は　あくまで大幻術
無限月読だ。
My end goal is a Super Genjutsu…
The Infinite Tsukuyomi!
I will put every human on
this planet under a single genjutsu…
この星すべての人間を
ひとつの幻術にはめる。
A single world that belongs
to nobody.
だれでもない　一つの世界。
戦いも　わだかまりもない
完璧な一つの世界。
One perfect world
without war or ill feelings.
個を捨てた単一の意識の中にこそ
真理がある。
Only within a single
collective consciousness…
where the individual has been
cast aside, can truth be found!
世界には　もはや　希望も未来も→
The world no longer needs hope,
a future or famous heroes.
名のある英雄もいらないのだよ。
十尾が不完全でも　復活すれば→
Even if incomplete,
once Ten Tails is revived,
無限月読の術を
組めるようになる。
the Infinite Tsukuyomi Jutsu
can be achieved.
そして　現実は終わり。
Then reality will come to an end…
あるのは　ただ無限に続く
たったひとつの終わりなき夢。
And all that will exist will be
a single unending dream…
that will last for all eternity!
《代わってくれ　九喇嘛》
Kurama, switch back!
俺には　父ちゃんがいた。
I had Dad, Mom, and Pervy Sage.
母ちゃんがいた。
エロ仙人がいた。
ガキは　英雄に憧れるもんだ！
Kids love looking up to their hero.
だから俺は
迷わないで　突っ走れる！
That's why I can keep running
forward without hesitation.
俺は　どの先代をも超える
火影になる！
I will become
the greatest Hokage o
それが俺の夢だ！　バカ野郎！
青春は
終わりにしたくはなくても→
夢は　いつか終わりにしなきゃ
ならないもんだ。
ああ　夢は叶えるものだ。
夢　夢　夢　夢いっぱい。
俺の夢は　年増の　オッパイ。
多くの夢が叶ってこそ
見えてくる真理。
（八尾）このタイミングで　性癖を
カミングアウトしていく勇気が→
すごいな　ビー。
個は　真実を見えなくさせる。
誰でもない俺の言葉こそ
世界の真理から導かれた言葉。
はっ！